brightroom.com 2016-05-18

# Privacy Policy | Backprint

Backprint.com® knows that you care how information about you is used and shared, and we appreciate your trust that we will do so carefully and sensibly. This Privacy Policy describes how Backprint.com gathers and disseminates information it obtains from you. By visiting Backprint.com, you are accepting the practices described in this Privacy Policy.

**What this Privacy Policy Covers**

This Privacy Policy covers treatment by Backprint.com® of personally-identifiable information that Backprint.com collects when you visit the site and that you provide when you purchase photos and/or photo-related products. This policy also covers treatment by Backprint.com of any personally-identifiable information that Backprint.com partners share with Backprint.com and which Backprint.com shares with its business partners. This policy does not apply to the practices of companies that Backprint.com does not own or control, or to people that Backprint.com does not employ or manage.

**Information Gathered When You Visit Backprint.com®**

Backprint.com® employs web browser cookies. A “cookie” is a small text file that a web site, when visited by a user, sends to that user’s browser which, in turn, may store some data on the user’s hard drive or memory. Backprint.com uses cookies to identify your visit session for customizing your user experience, for generating web site analytical data, and for Google Display Advertising and Remarketing with Google AdWords on third party websites.

Backprint.com’s “session cookies” are set to expire when the user closes the web browser. These session cookies are used to identify your visit session for e-commerce purposes and for maintaining your language choice from page to page. Backprint.com uses a persistent cookie to enhance your return visits to Backprint.com®.

Google Analytics uses persistent cookies to aggregate data about user visits to Backprint.com®. Backprint.com® will track your use of the site in order to gain aggregate data that may be analyzed for trends and statistics. Subject to the provisions of this Privacy Policy, Backprint.com® may use accumulated aggregate data for purposes including, but not limited to, marketing analysis, evaluation of services provided by Backprint.com®, and business planning.

Google Display Advertising and Remarketing with Google AdWords uses persistent cookies set by Google and DoubleClick to inform, optimize, and serve ads based on someone’s past visits to Backprint.com®. The website visitor may use features of their web browser to block or delete Backprint.com cookies, cookies used for Google AdWords, and / or cookies used for Google Display Advertising and Remarketing with Google AdWords from the user’s hard drive or memory. However, by disabling cookies, certain site features and functionality may no longer work properly or at all and the user may not see advertising on third part websites with reminders and special offers. You can opt-out of Google Display Advertising and Remarketing with Google AdWords ad by following Google’s instructions.

As you browse Backprint.com®, advertising cookies will be placed on your computer so that we can understand what you are interested in. Our display advertising partner, AdRoll, then enables us to present you with retargeting advertising on other sites based on your previous interaction with Backprint.com®. The techniques our partners employ do not collect personal information such as your name, email address, postal address or telephone number. You can visit this page to opt out of AdRoll and their partners’ targeted advertising.

Backprint.com uses the Gigya social networking management suite to enable some of the Backprint features and benefits tracking. When you login to the Gigya, Backprint will place cookies on your computer. If you do not allow third party cookies you may not be able to access and use features and benefits that require this tool.

Backprint.com may conduct surveys or other studies of its user base and use the results for marketing and planning purposes. Participation in such surveys is at the user’s option. Backprint.com reserves the right to disclose information provided by any user through such a survey, provided that no personal information identifying that user is disclosed. Circumstances under which Backprint.com would publicly disclose aggregate information include, but are not limited to, sharing survey results with partners and/or the site users, providing data to advertisers on user preferences and/or demographics, business planning, and publicizing overall usage data in press communications.

Disclosure of Personal Information

Backprint.com® may utilize user-provided email addresses to contact users on an individual basis. At no time, unless such disclosure is required by law, a governmental agency, or specifically authorized by the user, will Backprint.com disclose individual user personal information to unrelated third parties that is not publicly available.

Information Provided by Backprint.com® Partners

Backprint.com® may receive information from partners that you provided to them during your event registration as covered by your event registration agreement. Backprint.com may also receive information from partners related to your participation in the event, such as your timing and finish information. Backprint.com uses this information for marketing purposes as well as to customize certain products by including information specific to a particular participant.

Backprint.com will not provide any personally-identifiable information received from its partners to any third party. Partner-provided data may be aggregated demographically for use by Backprint.com and may be shared with partners.

**Links with other sites**

The Backprint.com® site contain links to other websites, whether owned or controlled by Backprint.com partners, or unrelated third parties. Please note that the privacy policies of those sites may differ from those of Backprint.com. Backprint.com is not responsible for the privacy policies and practices of any linked website. We encourage you to read the privacy policy of any website you may visit.

**Choice “Opt-in” Emails**

From time to time users may be given the opportunity to “opt-in” to receive site notifications, newsletters, or other information via email. Users may remove themselves from such services at their discretion. Any email sent to an “opt-in” list will include directions for how a user may remove himself or herself from the list, or a URL where the user may find such directions.

**Security**

To secure site integrity, Backprint.com® employs measures, including but not limited to security audits, use of encryption tools and software, and other reasonable security measures and procedures.

Backprint.com will not request or store a user’s Social Security Number. When Backprint.com offers items or services for sale where credit card information is required, Backprint.com will transmit and store that information in an encrypted format and in accordance with general industry practices, as deemed appropriate by Backprint.com.

Internal access to users’ private and nonpublic personal information is restricted to site administrators and individuals on a need-to-know basis.

**Enforcement**

In the event that Backprint.com® becomes aware that site security is compromised or nonpublic user information has been disclosed to unrelated third parties as a result of external activity, including but not limited to external security attacks, Backprint.com shall take reasonable measures which it deems appropriate, including but not limited to internal investigation and reporting, and notification to and cooperation with law enforcement authorities, notwithstanding other provisions of this Privacy Policy.

If Backprint.com becomes aware that a user’s personal information provided to Backprint.com has been disclosed in a manner not in accordance with this Privacy Policy, Backprint.com shall make reasonable efforts to notify the affected user, as soon as reasonably possible and as permitted by law, of what information has been disclosed, to the extent that Backprint.com knows this information.

**No Guarantees For Factors Beyond the Control of Backprint.com®**

While this Privacy Policy expresses the standards of Backprint.com® for maintenance of private data, Backprint.com is not in a position to guarantee that the standards will always be met. There may be factors beyond the control of Backprint.com (e.g., “script kiddies”, “crackers and other malcontents”) that may result in disclosure of data. As a consequence, Backprint.com disclaims any warranties or representations relating to maintenance or nondisclosure of private information.
